<?xml version="1.0"?>

<book>

    <page type="tailorTitle">
        <title>The Tailors Choice</title>
        <text>Clothe yourself in the finest metals\n\nBy RWTema</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorContents">

    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>!BETA Disclaimer!</section>
        <text>This mod is currently in early beta. No balancing has yet been attempted. Bugs will happen.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Introduction</section>
        <text>A good tinkerer should know that the world is a dangerous and evil place with many things wishing to kill you. While tools and weapons are important, a good set of armor is vital to a tinkers continuous survival.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Simple Armor Crafting</section>
        <text>Simple non-metal armor is a tinkerers first starting point for protection. These simple armor pieces are created in the part builder using the appropriate wooden patterns. However, this can only be done using simple non-metal materials, or relatively soft metals, such as iron and copper.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="crafting">
        <text>Wooden Pattern (Helmet)</text>
        <recipe>
            <name>armorPatternHelmet</name>
            <size>three</size>
        </recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="crafting">
        <text>Wooden Pattern (Chestplate)</text>
        <recipe>
            <name>armorPatternChestplate</name>
            <size>three</size>
        </recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="crafting">
        <text>Wooden Pattern (Leggings)</text>
        <recipe>
            <name>armorPatternLeggings</name>
            <size>three</size>
        </recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="crafting">
        <text>Wooden Pattern (Boots)</text>
        <recipe>
            <name>armorPatternBoots</name>
            <size>three</size>
        </recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Advanced Armor Crafting</section>
        <text>Armor made from even moderately hard metals cannot be made in the part builder. You must use a smeltery in order to melt down the metals into a molten liquid form (see Mighty Smelting). The molten metal can then be cast into an armor using the appropriate block cast.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorBlockCast">
        <text>Cast Helmet</text>
        <recipe>castHelmet</recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorBlockCast">
        <text>Metal Chestplate Cast</text>
        <recipe>castChestplate</recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorBlockCast">
        <text>Metal Leggings Cast</text>
        <recipe>castLeggings</recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorBlockCast">
        <text>Metal Boots Cast</text>
        <recipe>castBoots</recipe>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Damage Resistance</section>
        <text>Different types of armor are more effective at stopping attacks than others. This is measured by the damage resistance of the armor,</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Damage Threshold</section>
        <text>A tinkers natural inclination is to go for the strongest armors as soon as possible, but even weak armor has its important uses. If the damage of an attack is below the armors 'damage threshold', then it will be absorbed at a resistance rate of 80%. This means even weak armor will be incredibly strong against weak attacks.\n\nIf an armors natural resistance is already above 80%, then the damage threshold will not be calculated.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Modifiers</section>
        <text>Like a tinkers tools, an armor piece can be upgraded to give better stats and abilities.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Protection Modifiers</section>
        <text>Protection modifiers will grant additional protection against certain types of damage. This reduction is applied separately from the armors resistance and damage threshold. It is important to realize however that, all the protection modifiers of an armor set cannot reduce an attack by more than 80%.</text>
    </page>


    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>normal</modifier>
        <desc>Protection against 'normal' damage. This will protect against fire, explosion, projectiles and any physical based attacks. It won't protect against non-physical damage such as magical, poison or wither attacks.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>fire</modifier>
        <desc>Protects against fire damage.</desc>
    </page>


    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>explosion</modifier>
        <desc>Protects against shock waves caused by explosions.</desc>
    </page>


    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>projectile</modifier>
        <desc>Protection against damage caused by ranged projectiles..</desc>
    </page>


    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>magic</modifier>
        <desc>Protection against magical or non-physical attacks. Such as poison, potions of harming, wither attacks, etc.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>wither</modifier>
        <desc>Protection against the withering effect. This will not protect against the direct wither attack.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>fall</modifier>
        <desc>Protection against falling.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>anvil</modifier>
        <desc>Protection against falling anvils.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Additional Modifiers</section>
        <text>These modifiers do not absorb damage but give special properties.</text>
    </page>


    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>nightvision</modifier>
        <desc>Enables you to see perfectly in dark areas.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>haste</modifier>
        <desc>Zoom zoom zoom.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>health</modifier>
        <desc>Boosts the players health while being worn.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>attack</modifier>
        <desc>Arm servos boost base attack damage.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>knockback</modifier>
        <desc>Absorbs the velocity of an attack to prevent knockback.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>invisibility</modifier>
        <desc>Armor becomes invisible (you don't).</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>digspeed</modifier>
        <desc>Arms move like lightning.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>waterbreathing</modifier>
        <desc>Advanced Internal Rebreather.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>durability</modifier>
        <desc>Boosts durability of armor.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Modded Modifiers</section>
        <text>These modifiers require other mods to be installed.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>gogglesRevealing</modifier>
        <desc>Install Goggles of Revealing</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorModifier">
        <modifier>visBoost</modifier>
        <desc>Lining the interior of armor to boost wand performance.</desc>
    </page>

    <page type="tailorSection">
        <section>Modification Station</section>
        <text>Applying upgrades to your tools and armor can be a long and difficult process. The Modification Station has a specially constructed smooth surface to enable as many upgrades or modifiers as possible, in just a single operation.</text>
    </page>

    <page type="crafting">
        <text>Modification Station</text>
        <recipe>
            <name>modifyStation</name>
            <size>three</size>
        </recipe>
    </page>

</book>